Shubham Verma

Senior Android Developer

Profile

Android Developer

Software Developer with 6+ years of experience in designing, developing, testing, and debugging user interfaces, as well as creating and implementing source code proficient with **ANDROID** development, looking for opportunities to upskill my expertise in software development.

Employment History

Sr. Android Developer at Recro, Bengaluru

November 2022 — Present

- Working on banking applications for clients, such as LMS (Loan Management System) and collection systems, using Android development, Java, and Kotlin.
- Integrated Google Map Api and Place Api, Map My India, realm, and room.
- Worked on multi-module architecture using MVVM.
- Implemented data security, memory optimization techniques, and battery consumption optimization.

My role at Recro as a senior Android developer has allowed me to work on challenging **fintech projects** and further develop my skills in Android development.

Sr. Android Developer at Perseverance IT Solution Pvt.Ltd, Delhi

November 2021 — October 2022

- Developed TV and OTT applications using Java, Kotlin, and Exoplayer.
- **Utilized Exoplayer** to develop advanced features such as **adaptive streaming**, **offline playback**, and **live streaming**.
- Implemented Google Analytics.
- Developed apps using Kotlin Coroutines and Mp Android Chart.

Android Developer at Worked as a freelancer, Chandigarh

August 2020 — November 2021

- I worked on multiple Android, Java, and Kotlin-based projects.
- Worked on **Tensorflow** for Image classifications
- I gained experience in **image and video processing** using the **ffmpeg library**.
- Followed best practices for software development, including Agile methodologies, Git, and Jira, to ensure timely delivery of projects.

Jr. Android Developer at Smart Data Enterprises Pvt Ltd., Chandigarh

March 2019 — August 2020

Details

Jammu

India

9682170584

shubham.verma740@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

Java

Kotlin

MVP / MVC / MVVM
Architecture

Android Debugger

Firebase(Authentication, Real-time databases, Cloud Messaging)

Room Database

Hilt

GitHub

Android SDK

Crashlytics

Exoplayer

Jetpack Compose

Kotlin Coroutines

Mp Android Chart

FFmpeg for Image,Video Compressing

Jetpack libraries

XML Layouts(Responsive and adaptive UI design)

Material Design

- Developed FamiliasIn, a school management app that connects families directly with their educational centers. Technologies used: Android development, Java, Firebase.
- I developed Charmr, a dating application.(Similar to tinder)

Technologies used: Android development, Java, Kotlin, Firebase, Google Maps API.

Skills Developed:

- Worked on RXjava with Kotlin.
- Used Facebook native ads.
- Implemented FFmpeg for video compression.
- FFmpeg for Music with Images.
- Integrated Google Map Api and Place Api, Map My India.

JUNIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER at Applify, Chandigarh

February 2017 — March 2019

- Assisted in the development of **Android** applications using the latest technologies and best practices.
- Developed application UI using Android Studio and SDK, NDK lib was used for audio processing.
- Used Jetpack libraries.
- Implemented Firebase Messaging

Education

B.Tech, Chandigarh University, Chandigarh

2013 - 2017

Courses

Building Industry-Level Apps With Multi-Module Architecture, Phillipp lackner

Languages English

Hindi